Guide to the Hare Family Papers 1873-1962 (Bulk 1884-1930) MS 277
New-York Historical Society
Hare Family Papers
1873-1962 (Bulk 1884-1930)
New-York Historical Society
Hair family
MS 277
1 Linear feet (3 boxes)
The Hare Family Papers consist of the personal papers of New York City attorney Montgomery Hare (1870-1932), his wife Constance Parsons Hare (1873-?), and material by the Parsons family.
Provenance
Donation by Peter H. Hare, grandson of Montgomery and Constance Hare, 1999.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers.
Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.) See guidelines in Reading Room for details.
Biographical Summary For Montgomery Hare and Constance Parsons Hare:
Missing Title
1870 Montgomery Hare born in Orange, New Jersey to J. Montgomery Hare and Mary Meredith Hare. His siblings include Meredith, William, Morin, and Mary.
1873 Constance Parsons born to John E. Parsons and Mary McIlvaine Parsons, the youngest of six children including Mary (Mamie), Edith, Helen, Herbert, and Gertrude.
1884-1889 Montgomery Hare attends Groton School in Massachusetts.
1893 He receives his B.A. from Yale University.
1897 Montgomery Hare graduates from Columbia University Law School and is admitted to the bar.
1902-1906 He holds the office of Assistant Corporation Counsel in New York City.
1905 Montgomery Hare runs unsuccessfully for Alderman of the 31st Aldermanic District.
1908 With Thomas E. Rush, Montgomery Hare forms law partnership Rush & Hare.
1908 Montgomery Hare and Constance Parsons are married.
1909 First son Michael Meredith Hare born.
1911 Second son Montgomery Hare born.
1919 Montgomery Hare ends law partnership with Thomas E. Rush and establishes the firm, Shearn & Hare with Clarence J. Shearn.
1932 Montgomery Hare dies on July 8, at the age of sixty-two.
1953 Constance Parsons Hare turns eighty years old. The date of her death is unclear.
Scope and Content Note
The Hare Family Papers largely document the personal relationships within the Hare family and within the Parsons family, which was the family of Montgomery Hare's wife Constance. The bulk of the material is correspondence among family members. Neither Montgomery Hare's nor John E. Parsons's business affairs are represented within this collection.
The collection represents family relationships in the late nineteenth and early twentieth century. Parent/child relationships are represented through the letters to Montgomery Hare from his parents while he was away at school and later Hare's letters to his own children while they were away. Family relationships are also documented in the letters to Constance Parsons Hare from her children and her sisters.
The Library of Congress Name Authority File spells the family name "Hare" as "Hair."
Arrangement
The collection is arranged according to family member or type of material.
The papers are organized into the following seven series:
Missing Title
Series 1: Montgomery Hare, 1884-1930, undated
Series 2: Constance Parsons Hare, 1873-1962, undated
Series 3: John Edward Parsons, 1910-1916, undated
Series 4: Other Members of the Hare and Parsons Family, 1917-1929, undated
Series 5: Clippings, 1908-1929, undated
Series 6: Memorabilia, 1896-1951, undated
Series 7: Photographs, 1915-1953, undated
Related Material at The New-York Historical Society
Further material relating to Constance Parsons Hare and the Parsons family can be found within the Parsons Family Papers at the New-York Historical Society.
Separated Material
Oversize diplomas and photographs are stored in the small oversize case, drawer one.
New York (N.Y.) -- Social life and customs.; Correspondence.; Diplomas; Announcements; Invitations.; Theater programs.; Receipts (financial records); Poems; Report cards.; Examinations (documents); Families -- New York (State) -- New York.; Certificates.; Family -- New Jersey -- Orange.; Decedents' estates; Photographic prints.; New York (State) -- Genealogy.; Orange (N.J.) -- Social life and customs.; Clippings (information artifacts); Wills.; Agreements; negatives (photographs); Passports.; Insurance records; Parsons, John E. (John Edward), 1829-1915; Hare, Constance Parsons, 1873-; Hare, J. Montgomery; Hare, Mary Meredith; Hare, Michael Meredith; Hare, Montgomery, 1870-1932; Hare, Montgomery; Parsons family
- Series 1: Montgomery Hare, 1884-1930, undated
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains the personal materials of Montgomery Hare. It mainly includes incoming personal correspondence from family members and his wife-to-be, Constance Parsons. His correspondence also contains a 1930 form letter signed by Governor Franklin D. Roosevelt. The one folder of outgoing correspondence includes letters to his sons away at school and camp. The letters are arranged alphabetically by sender or recipient and then chronologically. The series also includes Hare's saved material such as writings, school records, policies, and certificates.
  - Montgomery Hare: Letters received from A-Hare, Marian, 1884-1930 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Montgomery Hare: Letters received from Hare, Mary Meredith, 1884-1892 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Montgomery Hare: Letters received from Hare, Mary Meredith, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Montgomery Hare: Letters received from Hare, Mary Meredith, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Montgomery Hare: Letters received from Hare, Michael Meredith, 1903-1925 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Montgomery Hare: Letters received from Parsons, Constance, 1900 July- 1901 Mar. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Montgomery Hare: Letters received from Parsons, Constance, 1901 Apr.-1901 Dec. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Montgomery Hare: Letters received from Parsons, Constance, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Montgomery Hare: Letters received from R-S, 1883-1930 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Montgomery Hare: Letters sent to Michael Meredith Hare and John E. Parsons, 1920-1929 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Academic Records from the Dearborn-Morgan School and the Groton School, 1885-1889 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Academic Records from Yale University, 1890-1893 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Academic Records from Yale University, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Montgomery Hare's Campaign for Alderman/Affiliation with Tammany Hall, undated, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Writings by Montgomery Hare, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Insurance Policy and Property Information for Montgomery Hare, undated, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Certificates Admitting Montgomery Hare as an Attorney for the Eastern District of New York, 1906, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Oversize Diplomas from Yale and Columbia, 1893, 1897 (Box OS, Folder 1)
- Series 2: Constance Parsons Hare, 1873-1962, undated
  This series contains materials relating to the life of Constance Parsons Hare. Most of the correspondence is from family members, particularly her sons and her sisters. Specific letters include a thank you letter from poet Edith Sitwell and two letters from Gertrude Parsons describing conditions in Germany and Paris after the end of World War I. Personal documents such as her will, a family tree, and a list of the monetary value of her property are also included.
  - Constance Parsons: Letters received from A-O, 1873-1952 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Constance Parsons: Letters received from P-T, 1907-1949 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Constance Parsons: Outgoing letters to various correspondents, undated, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Will of Constance Parsons Hare, 1940, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - List of auction and insurance values for property of Constance Parsons Hare, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Family Trees and Genealogical Information for Constance Parsons Hare, undated, 1945, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Series 3: John Edward Parsons, 1910-1916 undated
  This series includes the documents in the collection relating to John E. Parsons, the father of Constance Parsons Hare. Only one folder in this series contains correspondence, and it consists of letters written to John E. Parsons from his daughter, Gertrude Parsons. The other folders contain John E. Parsons's will and legal information regarding his estate.
  - John E. Parsons: Letters received from Gertrude Parsons, undated, 1910 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Will of John E. Parsons, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Documents relating to estate of John E. Parsons, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Series 4: Other Members of the Hare and Parsons Families, 1917-1929, undated
  This series consists of materials relating to other members of the Hare or Parsons families. It contains one folder of correspondence from Michael Meredith Hare and Montgomery Hare Jr. (the sons of Montgomery and Constance Parsons Hare), one folder of incoming and outgoing correspondence of Mary Parsons (Constance Parsons Hare's sister), and two passports for Gertrude Parsons (another sister of Constance Parsons Hare).
  - Michael Meredith Hare and Montgomery Hare, Jr.: Letters sent to various correspondents, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Mary Parsons: Letters sent and received, 1923, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Passports for Gertrude Parsons, 1917, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Series 5: Clippings, 1908-1929, undated
  This series consists of one folder of newspaper or magazine clippings that mention members of the Hare or Parsons family. Many of the clippings are wedding announcements for Montgomery and Constance Parsons Hare. The one folder of clippings unrelated to either family contains mostly articles on local and national politics.
  - Clippings regarding Hare and/or Parsons Family Members, 1908, 1926, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Clippings, unrelated to Hare and/or Parsons Family, undated, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Series 6: Memorabilia, 1896-1951, undated
  The memorabilia series includes saved ephemera such as invitations, receipts, programs, a brochure, and a menu. Although some of the theater programs attribute plays to Montgomery Hare, it is unclear if the playwright was Montgomery Hare, the elder, or his son of the same name.
  - Invitations and Announcements, undated, 1896-1910 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Receipts, 1917, 1921, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Theater Programs, 1891-1951 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Travel Brochures and Menu, 1922-1923 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Series 7: Photographs, 1915-1953, undated
  The series includes snapshots and posed portraits. They are divided into the following categories: photographs of members of the Hare family, photographs of members of the Parsons family, and unidentified subjects. Although many of the subjects are identified on the backs of the photos, most of the images are undated.
  - Photographs, Members of Hare Family, 1915-1953 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Photographs, Members of Parsons Family, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Photographs, Unidentified people, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Oversize Portrait Photographs of Montgomery Hare, Constance Parsons Hare, and John E. Parsons, undated, 1913 (Box OS, Folder 1)